The introduction to the race.
I think it should come for free.
Number four, Alan Austin.
Peter F. Tinez.
Welcome again to the Natatorium at the Nanjing Olympic Sports Centre.
Today, after six days of outstanding swimming events, the attention switches to the diving pool and the start of five days of competition on the springboard and platform.
We have individual medals as the ultimate prize for men and women at the classic heights of 3 and 10 metres to look forward to.
Plus, we conclude with an innovative team event which will combine men and women, springboard and platform.
More of that later, but we start with the women up on that 10 metre platform.
Well, if there's one sport China has every right to host at the very highest level, it's certainly diving.
Just confirming today's program for you, a preliminary followed by the final event later today.
Of course the origins of the sport can be traced back to this country to a thousand years ago but now in the 21st century China dominates the sport at Olympic and World Championship level.
Can they signpost an extension of their gold in the era over the next few days with a clean sweep of the titles here at the Youth Olympic Games?
Seventeen other countries will be trying to do something about that.
Encouraging crowd to see this first preliminary session.
Crowd's expected to build as we go through the days of competitions.
Let me explain a little bit about the format here.
The qualification process for the diving here in Nanjing is a little involved.
FINA held an official qualifying competition in March in Guadalajara in Mexico.
The top nine divers in each event won qualifying places for these games for their country and not just themselves.
So a number of the divers from that competition are not here, but their countries are still represented.
Then the host China was guaranteed a place of course and there were two more universality places which could be offered.
For example in this event the extra place was granted to Canada who are of course extremely strong in women's diving.
The format is also a little different.
Eight dives for the women today at 10 meter.
Four dives with a total degree of difficulty adding up to no more than 7.6.
Just seeing here the divers who will be getting us underway this morning.
Each of them with eight dives.
These dives are chosen from four specified routes.
Then there are four more dives without any degree of difficulty limit, where the divers have a free rein to show us what they can do.
These are also drawn from a range of groups.
That does sound a little bit complicated, but don't worry too much about the technicalities, just sit back and enjoy the show.
One other difference I should point out, which will help to make this morning even more competitive, the marks from the first four dives, those are the ones in the limited category, are carried into the final.
where as usual the divers will compete in reverse order with how they finish in these preliminaries.
I'll take you through that again as the competition evolves.
Your on-screen graphics will explain how the scoring and everything works quite clearly.
And as I said, you can just marvel at what is likely to be a very high-standard competition.
Diving very much a young person's sport, so you really can expect some terrific standards here.
Final note on the judging, of course.
allocate points out of ten in half a point of grades.
Each nine has allocated a degree of difficulty.
Seven judges, the top two marks, the lowest two marks, are all discarded and the middle three marks are then multiplied by the degree of difficulty.
That gives you your points score.
Hope you got all that.
China absolutely dominated as they do in so many international competitions in these first Youth Olympic Games four years ago in Singapore.
A clean sweep when there were just four events.
There were three and ten.
As China so often tend to do, they managed the clean sweep.
So the diving competition here in Nanjing finally gets underway.
These competitors will be so keen to get into that pool.
Ganna Krasnoshlyk from Ukraine will get us underway with a forward one and a half somersault.
These early dives have quite a low degree of difficulty, so it's all about the execution.
The points scores you'll see will be quite high for these, so you really have to make sure they get the dive as flawless as possible.
The tariff on Ganna's opening dive is only 1.6.
7.5 gives her 36 points.
Second bout, Gratia Leydon Mahoney from the United States.
She's 18 years of age.
She opens in a forward one and a half somersault in the piked position.
That too is a 1.6 tariff dial.
Now the judges will be breaking down the dive into its different stages, take off, various positions through the dive and of course that entry position which, although it isn't everything, is important because it does tend to leave that final impression on the judges.
Gratia there with a 2.7 and a 7.5, 34.40.
Ingrid de Oliveira won the bronze at the qualifying event in Mexico, a girl from Brazil, 18 years of age and she is one of the more favored divers in this competition.
She opens with a forward one and a half somersault pike.
A nice relaxed opening dive.
Hands together there, punching a hole through the water.
7.5, 36.
There won't be a big difference in these scores with the low tariff dives.
As the competition unravels, things will change.
Katsiarina Hitzner is next from Belarus.
She is just 16 years of age.
Forward one and a half somersault piked 1.6.
As we said, it's all about execution and you can't really afford to make too many significant mistakes with these opening dives.
And Katzyarina not really getting the entry as she would have wanted.
And her score down among the sixes there, 28-80.
Not the best start for her.
Salah Carolina Perez Beltran from Colombia.
He's just 17 years of age.
She has a forward one and a half somersault point.
This guy was the
for all the diners in this first round.
Nice and relaxed.
Remember that we get the benefit of those replays.
The judges don't.
They have to hit their marker button straight away.
3-7s and a 33-60 for the Old Columbia.
Molly Carlson from Kamila.
She is the
Youngest diver here in Nanjing, who would one-half somersault.
She's not 16 till next week like some of these girls.
She's also competing on the three-metre springboard.
A little bit untidy in the final stages.
3.6.5 31.20 Wu Shengping really applause ripples around this arena for China's young diver.
Not expected as ever of every Chinese diver.
very nice coach likes it you can hear almost the success of the diver especially when you get to the the bigger competitors in the men's and that rip they talk about very elegant line nice position out punching the hole so upright in the entry into the water there
Straight to the top of the pile, 40 points there.
Lu Shengping putting down a very early marker.
This is Lo Ji Yi, who's a quite experienced Malaysian diver, competed at the Commonwealth Games.
Great variety in the experience of these young women.
Maybe a noise as she enters the water.
Cory, I love it.
Very slim, slight, only 5 foot 3.
37 kilograms, 103 pounds.
45-20.
Notice the discrepancy in some of the marks that shows that this is a sport of our opinion.
Can't get quite a range.
Maha Huda from Egypt another 16 year old the same forward one and a half somersault pint
Just falling away there in the entry.
The legs got really held all the way through that guy.
And so the marks down in the 6.5s, 31.20.
Alain Calogny from France, 17 years of age, from Rennes.
with one and a half somersaults piped in.
He's also in the 10 metre qualifying event in Mexico.
A nice entry position held all the way through into the water.
Down to the judges, of course, of what they think.
And they liked it as well.
Some eight and a halves in there.
39-20.
Very good start for the French girl.
Alejandro Arrozco Lossa is on paper the girl most likely to challenge the Chinese supremacy here.
She is an established international diver with a full Olympic silver medal in the 10 meter synchronized event with the highly regarded Paola Espinosa of Mexico.
Mexico, a real powerhouse of diving at an international level, a great tradition.
Right back to those clips at Acapulco, but 33.60 was not a blazing start for her.
Divers will be pleased to have just got that feel of the watering competition for the first time and straight away Wu Shengping goes to the top of the pack but it is very early in this competition but remember these marks will count later.
Round two of eight, remember.
Gana Klaznoszlik from Ukraine.
Ukraine getting success at international levels as well in men's and women's competition.
In with one and a half somersault piked, 2.0 the tariff here.
opposing herself at the top of the dive.
Judges will look for how tight that pike position is.
Tried right up onto the knees.
Good position there from the Ukrainian.
And again a good straight entry pulled right through the water.
46 points.
Gratia Leydon Mahoney.
2012 World Junior Champion at three meters competing in both events here in Nanjing.
Inward one and a half somersault piked for the young American.
Perhaps slightly more successful on the springboard than the platform.
Although she's competed in the World Series and Grand Prix events in the FINA program.
And she has got 43 points from her second dive.
Now, Ingrid de Oliveira of Brazil, 18 years of age.
There's a lot of water there.
Just a continuing of the rotation there.
Foxy Elena Hitzner of Belarus.
He's from Minsk.
He was second in the European Junior Championships last year.
He would have won the half somersault.
He's the guy here, remember?
good position on entry.
A little heavy.
You can see that the line of the legs are way from the perpendicular and at heavy splash he lies there with just 33 points.
Sara Carolina Perez Beltran from Colombia, again a country with quite a strong diving presence internationally.
She didn't compete at the qualifying event.
I think she's quite good into the entry position she would have wanted there.
Again you can see from this angle just falling away from the vertical there.
and 31 points not a great return from her second dive Molly Carlson her opening dive not really setting her on the way she would have wanted the girl from Thunder Bay in Ontario 16 next month
interesting character.
All the Canadian diamonds, especially the girls, come from Quebec, based in Montreal.
She's on a bit of a limb out there in Thunder Bay in Ontario.
It's the work of the coach there under direction from the international coaches back in Quebec.
That's tidier from Molly.
Three sevens giving her 42 points.
Trying to have nine more divers in the FINA World Rankings at this event.
And Wu Xiangping is not one of them.
We have an absolute production line.
And the crowd responding there quite predictably.
It's not going to be until we get to the latter dives that we'll really see her
showing her best but so hard to pick faults in that lovely relaxed clean entry hardly a ripple oh yes 54 points three nines
Interesting to see just what standard of points the judges set really on this the opening competition.
Are they going to be keen to dole out those nines and tens which need to be earned but do get the crowd going.
This is Lo Ji.
And Malaysia too has become quite a force in world diving.
Her hero is of course Pandalela Rinong Pham.
Who won two silvers four years ago in Singapore and then went on to become a real star in Malaysia.
First female Olympic medalist, Pandalela.
That's her heroine and two eight and a halfs in an eight is a very good score indeed.
Maha Muda.
You might also see her named down as Maha Abdel Salam as well.
It's the same girl that did compete in the qualifying competition of 16.
Talking to her coach and he said sorry that
She was only able to go to compete in the qualifying event because she finished her exams.
The educational standards are very strict indeed.
Good pike position there in Egypt.
And it's not easy for them to combine the training with the education standards.
44 points there for Maha.
Alain Kelly from France.
competing in the Grand Prix in Bolzano earlier this year to give her a first taste of international competition.
Quickly into her dive.
Nice sound on the dive there.
Really relaxed.
Good position held right the way through the entry.
judges liked it as well 50 points that's a very good encouragement there really getting off to the flying start for the olympic silver medalist
I can see the little heavy there again.
A powerful diver compared to the extremely slender Chinese girl for example.
That's a very well-held entry there though, really tight control of her core strength.
3.8 to 48 is a little bit more what we would have been expecting.
Two rounds of the competition then.
Wu Shengping really setting the standards but the French girl really doing very well indeed.
Still waiting for the other established stars to make a bit of a show but very much early stages here.
On to round three.
Grainian coach there watching for Gunnar Kozlozlik.
He will perform a backdive pike.
The tariff here is 1.8.
The 18-year-old has quite a good degree of experience to bring into this competition.
He competed at the World Championships in Barcelona last year.
Just missed out on a place in the final, finishing 13th in the semi-final.
He's got 41.40 there with the third guy.
from the United States.
Seventh after two rounds.
This backdye.
Well, it's another disappointing set of scores there.
Three sixes.
In with the Oliveira.
Six.
Another Brazilian goal.
One of the fancy divers for a potential medal.
It's all about eradicating any unnecessary mistakes in this first round.
Performing these lower tariff dives as cleanly as possible.
Just the feet just slipping away there and causing the extra splash.
37, 37, 80.
It's Yelena Hitzner from Belarus.
On the stand forward somersault here.
She's got to show she's in control of that gymnastic maneuver to the judges before she releases.
But for the push off to see how much height she can get.
Well there wasn't a lot of spring off the platform there.
It was a bit more of a fall straight through into the dive.
So hard to hold it there and then get the launch you want.
38 points going down as far as six.
Salah Kalalina, Perez Beltran.
Back dive piked worth 1.8.
Back in 10th.
The judges get a good side on view.
There's a four on one side three on the opposite.
Seeing all those high chairs just as she goes for the water there.
A lot of water splashed on the entry which leaves a bad impression as she only scores 32-40.
Wally Carlson.
Angus Diver at the games.
An American junior champion last year.
Backdive piked.
That's what we're looking at.
Compete at the 10 metre event in the qualifier.
Falling away there on entry.
But still scoring 40-50, which is a decent return.
Wang Shengping.
Very composed young lady there.
17 years of age.
She is from Nanjing, so loads of local support.
Very graceful diver indeed.
Holding out, reaching for the water.
Again, very hard to pick pokes in that.
And three nines shows that they pretty well couldn't already pretend, which would be unbelievable on the very first day of competition.
Lojai from Malaysia.
Quite a busy summer competing at the Commonwealth Games Malaysia had a very strong games
in Glasgow where the games are in Glasgow.
The diving was actually at the Commonwealth Pool in Edinburgh nearby and Malaysia had an excellent competition with the men following on from the women who've been the stronger internationally.
Three 7.5s there.
Moha Gouda
back one and a half somersault with half a twist a little bit more movement in that dive for the crowd to enjoy into the twist and out
and the arms reaching.
It's all about stopping that rotation once you get into the somersaults that are tidily executed by Maha with 44 points.
Hélène Calogny who's made a very good start, 50 points with her second dive.
What did she do with this reverse dive?
Piked.
Her coach was telling me that if she could finish in the top six that would be a very good return for her.
Reaching out for the water there but not really seeing the dive all the way through the entry.
And down in the 6.5s, 37.05.
It's just quite as good as her second dive.
will have serious medal ambitions in this competition but she'll want to make sure she gets these first four dives which will count in the final absolutely right.
Quickly out into the entry position.
2.877.5.
Still more to come I suspect.
So after three rounds Wu Shengping is really starting to open up a lead there.
1.45 to 1.27.
And down the bottom there's always a fairly substantial spread of marks from 1.45 to 97.
it's all about putting together a program especially today with eight dives to get through five is the normal in senior competition and it's all about keeping the big mistakes keeping the double bogeys off your card to make a golfing analogy it's all about consistency
and then hopefully pulling out the big point scorer, if it really matters, Kana Krasnoshlyk, the Ukraine reverse dive pint, is her fourth time.
To get some height off that platform.
Holding it nicely on entry, the position.
And 43.70 for Gallo.
Quite consistent so far.
Gratia Leydon Mahoney from the United States.
The great diving tradition going back, Gratia.
All the Americans are on there.
Lost a little bit of ground in some areas.
Reverse dive piked.
So many divers.
She used to be involved in gymnastics and used to play hockey, ice hockey to them.
20.85 is her score there.
Ingrid de Oliveira back in seventh.
Still waiting for a bit of a show from the Brazilian girl.
Reverse dive.
1.9 the tariff remember.
That was a lot nicer sounding dive.
Very clean entry.
Quickly through that pike there.
The judge is not desperately impressed.
39.90.
Katja Rina-Fitzner from Belarus.
for the first time.
Piked.
We go on to the more complex times.
There is a lot more to appreciate what's going in, a lot more to see what goes wrong exactly.
37.05.
I can't wait these competitors from arriving in Nanjing to play with the rest of the team.
We're very pleased to finally get into their competitive stride.
Perez Beltrero of Colombia.
Down in 11th place after three rounds.
Just falling away to the left we get a different perspective than the judges when we're looking from that camera angle of course.
6.5, 37.05.
Great shapes there in the scores.
Molly Carlson from Canada.
Big local star out in Thunder Bay where they really take it to her.
André Puglio Deschamps is her coach down there, international coach.
Oh, that one completely went to pieces.
Heart goes out, especially to these young divers in diving.
Well, it doesn't go right.
It really doesn't go right at all.
And you can see that she just lost control of that through the air.
As you know that, 4 is 22.80.
I'm going to put that behind you.
A little wall-shamping.
The forward one, the half somersault, one twist, 2.1.
She does have the most involved highest tariff program of all the divers, not surprisingly.
The crowd responding there because we're just starting to see the first signs of complexity in the diving.
So elegant, relaxed, so polite in the way they carry the diving.
Three nines again, nines right across the board.
Boy, he's going to take some slopping.
Mo Jai from Malaysia, 16 year old.
Fina ranking of 38.
I thought all these girls do have a Fina ranking, you need to be in the senior competitions.
That one-and-a-half somersault, half a twist.
These very slight Asian divers are naturally very elegant into the water.
You get to the men, you'll see the different body shapes.
You can make a difference.
2.8 or 7.5.
47 points.
Maha Udha.
Back to the reverse dive piked here.
Reverse dive of course when they dive back towards the board as opposed to being out away from it.
Charity.
Nicely completed.
7.5, 42.75.
Pretty consistent with her marks, all in the 40s.
L.A. Kehlanyi from France had that great second dive, scored 50 points.
She's got a back one and a half somersault with half a twist to try to get back to that standard.
She's ranked third so far, but having a nice start.
Check the rotation before entry.
Pretty decent.
Seven and a halfs out the middle of the pack, 45.
Arkadro Orozco-Losa starting to get into her competitive stride.
Armstand forward somersault, this is 1.9.
Up into that gymnastic position.
to hold it show control get you those good snappy push off the platform
That's where the power comes in, which is probably asking quite a lot of these young women to have that real arm strength to push up from that platform.
We'll get to some of the big lads in the men's 10 meter, you'll see a little bit more what I mean.
The 45-60 is still a nicely executed dive, she's been fairly consistent.
Right, we've got the lower tariff dives out the way.
Wu Shengping really is showing what she can do.
And Malaysia and Mexico season performers starting to show there as well.
Round five, now we start to get going.
This is where the dives become a lot more complex.
A lot more to impress the crowd, a lot more to go wrong.
Ganna, Klaas Noschlik with an inward two and a half somersault, piked.
This is worth 2.8.
She's fifth after those restricted dives.
A long wait at the top of that position on the platform.
She will have a trigger.
Now she goes.
bit in that dive successfully completed 53 20 Gratia Mahoney reverse two and a half somersault 2.8 the tariff here
She too has had a couple of years on the FINA circuit, so knows what the pressure is like.
Point Pacey through the somersaults.
Of course it's all about controlling that spin speed in the tuck position there.
I have to try and put the brakes on, get into a good entry position.
56.
Room for improvement there.
Ingrid Oliveira, back two and a half somersault, one and a half twists.
We're up to 3.2 with the degree of difficulty for the Brazilian girl.
I think she had a problem just putting the brakes on that dive.
Through the twists.
Not the tidiest of pike positions and a rather heavy entry.
Good six points by five counting there.
in the two and a half somersault 2.8 who's her first optional dive for the 16 year old from Linz in Belarus.
And of course the arty is getting through your sun assaults in enough time to give you the room to open out into a good clean entry position.
She came up a little bit short in that.
The quicker your spin speeds, of course, the harder it is to put the brakes on.
They're not really getting through it in the right proportions there.
Four and a halves, 37.80, not the greatest.
Perez Beltran of Colombia.
She has her back two and a half somersault with half a twist.
Piked the degree of difficulty a more modest 2.6.
A bit of a response from the audience for that one.
She's got through it all in quite the way as intended.
Opening up into the position, just about completing it.
A bit hurried, 44.20 for the Colombian.
young Molly Carlson young because she's 16 next week 10th great experience for her that's what these games are really about top-level experience forward three and a half somersault 2.7 well she was very quick through her spins in the tuck position but didn't really have the control it needed to deal with it enthusiastic
Quickly through, then it starts to get a bit untidy towards the end.
Only 35.10.
Now, to the top of the pile, Wu Shengping.
Local girl.
forward three and a half somersault, three point zero.
Wow.
She really is showing her pedigree very early on in this competition.
With snuffing away at the top there.
Quickly, look how quickly she is through that somersault.
Great pike position, lovely entry, absolutely vertical.
9.5 that is the dive so far in here 85 50 that is top
No, Jai has to follow that, put that totally out of range.
They stack up on the boards to be ready to dive.
Forward three and a half, somersault there, piked.
3.0 for the 16-year-old Malaysian girl.
Very attractive diver.
Very good pike position.
Fast.
Judges liked it.
Got an 8.5 there to count.
73.50.
A really furthest competition is beginning now.
Maha Houda.
Sixth.
Off to the limited dives.
She's now got a full three and a half somersault.
That's 2.7.
Tucked position here.
really get through the rotations in time to get the entry position she might have wanted.
Heats the height off the platform.
Reaching for it and still continuing the movement to the rotational movement on entry and that keeps her down to about
Hello.
The attractive diver in her shapes as she goes through the air.
Relaxed on entry, straining there, 54.05.
Top 10 would be good and she's looking on course for that sort of performance.
With the final to come, Alejandro Arasco Loffa, the synchro silver medalist from London 2012.
completing this fifth round with an inward three and a half somersault 3.2.
The entry was not quite as upright as ideal.
She's not really been as consistent as we might have expected.
62-40, six fives.
Well the competition has started properly and Wu Shengping again increasing her lead at the top.
Lo from Malaysia doing well.
And it's young Molly Carlson bringing up the rear at the moment.
Remember, these dives won't count in this evening.
If you're not used to watching diving on a regular basis, you will have realised by now that it's extremely well organised in terms of cracking on through the competition.
The girls are always on the next level of the platform stairs ready to perform, so we're into six of eight dives now.
Ganna Kranoschlik from Ukraine, who is back in fifth position for the 18-year-old from Kiev.
Ghana with a towel on the end of the platform there.
Gives some of the divers more confidence when they run towards that platform that they're going to get the right grip.
It's all a bit untidy there.
And the mark is down in the 6-5, 58-50.
Gratia Leighton-Mahoney.
Eight after five rounds.
from the girl from Newton in Massachusetts
Lucky enough to have Tracy Bird, her coach, out here with her.
All the divers quite that lucky.
Have the international coaches look after them.
In with three and a half somersault.
The divers were 3.2 but she seemed to have a problem.
Again putting those brakes on.
Stopping the rotations.
Getting into the upright position.
Into the tuck.
And just running out of room really.
Five's 48 points there for Gratia.
Ingrid de Oliveira.
Seventh after five rounds.
Arm stand back double somersault.
One and a half twists.
Unusual position to get up into the arm stand.
Coming in from a side angle there.
Quickly up into it though.
Show the judges you're in control.
Look for the push off.
Long hold.
Couldn't really complete all she wanted to get through in time for the correct entry.
through the twists.
All a little hurried.
You're getting a huge amount of fight off the board, 59.20.
Kasia Lina-Pizner from
Belarus.
She was 12th in the qualifying event with 150 points behind the winner so she could just hold back a bit of ground in this competition.
She will have progressed.
That didn't go right at all.
Coming out, looking for the entry position but just not finding it.
And just 25.65 for that dive, what a disaster.
Perez Beltrano has a forward 3.5 sub-assault, 3.0 the degree of difficulty.
Again, it's the over rotation.
Quite nice at the top of the dive.
Nice spins there, but you can't control it.
43.50
Pamela Ware is her big heroine who was at these games four years ago.
Now an established international competitor, particularly strong in synchro events.
Arm stand back, triple somersault, she needs to get up there.
Doesn't look very comfortable fighting it.
Keen to get out of it as well.
Never really convinced that she had that dive under control from the moment she went into the arm stand position.
Trying to get extra drive with the legs out of it.
Trying to hold a decent entry position.
52.18 down in the five, five and a halves.
The whole mood in the pool changes when
The local girl Wu Xing Ping steps forward.
In with three and a half somersault, 3.2.
Quickly over to tiptoes.
Absolute composure.
Lovely stuff.
quickly through the spins reaches out and a very good entry position and again right out of the top drawer 86 40 she's looking in a different class from Malaysia 16 years
of age looking very nice so far second place she's got a back two and a half somersault with half a twist this one just worth 2.6 only 5.3 47 kilos other than three pounds depending on where you rate these things
Divers at different stages with their development of course.
Three seven and a halfs, 58-50.
Mahoguda.
Arms down, forward elbow, sun assault.
This is just 2.4.
Fighting the balance there.
Got to show the judges she's got the position under control.
Now she has.
Gosh, she pulled it all the way.
Very interesting story around this Egyptian driver.
They don't have an indoor pool in Egypt, so can only train with the weapons OK.
So winter is a bit of a no-no for her.
52.80 she's got there, which is a steady return.
Aleh Kaloni has been impressive in the two and a half somersault point position.
Waste much time at the top of the platform there before triggering into her movement.
Nice height position.
Really decent job of it.
61.60.
More encouragement for her.
Orozco Mosa from Mexico.
Round stand back double somersault, one and a half twist, 3.2.
It's the highest tariff dive in the competition.
in, never got that one under control, hurried through the arm stand.
expecting a bit more from somebody with her pedigree but we're not really getting it so far.
48 points, I mean she can put this behind her in the final but she can do better.
Six rounds gone, and romping away at the top of the field in this preliminary competition is Wu Shengping, Lowe of Malaysia, and Cologny of France.
Very impressive.
And the spread of points is 270.
Again, it's very encouraging.
Seven of eight dives then.
Pull herself up to fifth and has a reverse two and a half somersault tucked to point eight degree of difficulty.
Well, she will not be rushed at the top of the platform there to her credit.
It's an attack and a heavy entry.
4760.
Gratia made Mahoney eight out of six rounds going off to Stanford University later in the year.
Four, they would say, in America in the autumn or two of us might describe it.
weight sports programs in many of these American universities.
Arm stand back double somersault one and a half twist that's a nice starting position can she capitalize on that not really
Never got me height off the platform really, only extra and came up short in the end and didn't get the entry position.
59.20 for the North American girl.
The Olivera, 18-year-old Brazilian.
He's competing at both fights here in Nanjing for the three and a half somersault.
energetic bit of sun assaulting there the idea if they can do is to stay as close to the platform as possible that she was diving quite a long way out into the water there and again never really had the core strength to stop the rotations ends up with 49.50
Katharina Fitzner from Belarus.
competing in the recent European Junior Championships at this height.
At this height he was ninth.
Though she's had a silver in the previous year, the European Junior Championships, quite recent for a few of the divers we'll see over the next few days were competing there.
Up into that arm stand before the back thumb somersault with half a twist.
Ankles together.
She's got it under control now.
very difficult for the younger divers not having the chance to build up the body strength the divers do a huge amount of gym work to give them that ability to get the extra height off the platform and give themselves more room for the dive to evolve down there 40-50
Pérez Beltran of Colombia down in 10th place now has a back two and a half somersault 2.9 hiked position No
The judges regard that as a completed dive or not.
To the pike out of it.
Never really got into any position to make some sort of an entry.
Well, she still gets 2465 for it.
It's a tough sport.
got to get consistency across your diving schedule cannot afford a disaster it's going to take you out of contention molly carlson back two and a half sun assault again she can't really complete the dive to any degree of satisfaction
fight position was decent enough but again she's well short there's a 770 she's generating speed through the somersaults to give herself time
not pushing it up to say.
Let's see how it should be done.
Arms down, back double somersault, one and a half twist, 3.2 for Wu Shengping who is miles ahead on top of the field and looking brilliant.
Quickly up, taking on those wrists, lovely start position.
This is one of those diners where her natural elegance is going to make her look really good no matter what errors she may actually put into the dive.
Entry wasn't the best she's come up with but it's still 81.60.
Loh Chyee has looked good, very good.
16 year old, looking to carry on the great improvement made in Malaysian diving in the last four or five years, no more.
Armstand back double somersault, one and a half twist here, 3.2 the degree of difficulty.
She is second after six rounds.
May not have been her best so far.
Her fifth dive was her Mastonka with 73.50.
She's dropped back to 60.80 with that one.
Courage is low overall today.
Maha Nida.
in the two and a half somersault, just to continue the conversation I enjoyed with her coach.
He gets to train maybe once or twice a week, multi work and dry land work in the winter.
Again, didn't really
get the whole job done through the air there but Egyptian diving is starting to progress and this is a very important competition for them in terms of encouragement.
Six is 50-40 for Maha.
Ke Lung Yee has been impressive.
Armstand back double somersault, half a twist, 2.7.
Her schedule only has two 2.8s as the two most difficult dives.
Oh, she was never really in control of that, was all a bit rushed.
that may well cost her when she actually got into the dive it was quite tiny but a little bit carried at the top maybe yes judges have penalized her for that 450 there after some good work today still fourth without really dazzling
forward three and a half somersault here.
Getting just a little short.
Ready getting the entry position she might have wanted.
58.50.
Well, Wu Xingping is possibly too young to be giving a master class, but I don't want to describe it any other way.
Malaysia, Mexico towards the top there.
One more round to go.
Final round of eight dives then.
Gana Krasnoshnik of Ukraine with a forward two and a half somersault one twist.
Pike's position worth 2.9 to end her first session's work.
coach giving some encouragement.
A busy morning for these girls because only 11 of them so the time in between their dives has been quite short and they've also had eight rounds to get through so it's been quite hard work for them.
56.55 to end today's efforts for Ghana.
Gratiot, Ladan Mahoney from the United States.
Back one and a half, sub-assault, three and a half, twists for her eighth time.
Well, like all these competitors, she will be pleased to have got the first session out of the way.
It's just a little bit messy through that.
59.40 to finish up her work.
Ingrid de Oliveira from Brazil.
In with three and a half somersault tucked.
3.2 is her concluding dive.
That really got a bit untidy towards the end there.
Just to remind you of the format, you have eight rounds here this morning.
The first four rounds score again in the final and then they've got four more dives.
So one of the workers come this morning, 52.80 for Ingrid.
Eleven after seven rounds.
for the girl from Belarus.
Back two and a half somersault with half a twist here.
Okay, not the tidiest.
Maybe they're getting a little bit tired, finding it difficult to sustain their form all the way through the competition, which is absolutely crucial.
40.30 there, not the greatest end.
Perez Beltran with her final dive.
In with three and a half sub-assault tucked position.
Tenth going into this final round.
Quickly through her three and a half sub-assaults.
just falling away out of the vertical there on entry which helped to increase all that splash and 48 points for Sara Carolina young Molly Carlson a 15 year old from Bundabay in Ontario Canada
Reverse two and a half somersault tucked, two point eight to complete her program.
It's a better ending for her as well.
Coach was saying she's got about nine dives she's really comfortable with.
They only have a certain number within their locker at this stage in their development of course.
46-20 there.
It has been a superb demonstration by Wu Shengping so far.
Back two and a half somersault, one and a half twists.
For the local girl from Nanjing.
they'll be going home this crowd and saying you've got to come along to the final just to watch this girl because like so many Chinese divers she looks something a little bit special very good hardly a flaw right from start to finish 80 points
hammering out the big scores all the way through.
More scores in the 80s for her.
Lo Jai has had a good first session in the pool here.
Second
silver would be a great reward when it comes to the final plenty to go before then in the three and a half somersault 3.2 to finish can she sign off with an encouraging note yes
Very nice.
Very impressive so far.
Composed.
Neat.
Quick through the air and clean into the water.
81.60.
Well done.
Mahaguda.
From Egypt.
forward two and a half somersault one twist last dive was a bit of rye and that one also not really completed do any satisfaction quite a tall diver and running out of room again the legs
Quite an angle there on entry and that means it's down in the fours with 34.80.
Another young woman to watch, Elie Calogny of France.
10th in the qualifying event remember, back in March.
She's obviously been putting in some good work because she looks pretty good here.
It does go into her dive rather quickly at the top, which doesn't always suggest great control.
She's just having hard work to keep her standards right through the eight rounds, which is a lot.
Alejandra Awoska-Lorfa completes the show.
She's gradually quietly worked her way up into third position, which is a bit nearer the form guide for the Olympic silver medalist.
Back two and a half somersault, one and a half twist, 3.2.
She does bring such a lot of pedigree into this competition.
The youngest Olympic medalist in Mexican history at London.
Fifteen then.
Seventeen now.
That's not one of her best there.
Seems to 240 to finish with.
That is the end of the competition in this preliminary round of the Women's 10m platform.
Wu Shengping, absolutely superb from gun to whistle.
Excellent.
All qualify of course, all come back for the final.
They will have learned from this first session.
Plenty to whet the appetite then.
And we have seen some encouraging performances and also just what a test it can be at this Olympic level for young divers.
Can they deal with the pressure?
Can they produce their really best form?
Many of their coaches and they themselves will find out over the next few days of competition.
But one diver has really shone.
So last run away in the diving competition, first session of five days of diving here in Nanjing and that has whetted the crowd's appetite I'm sure and certainly all the home and local support.